<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matthew Yang | Singapore</title>
    <description>Jekyll website project</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>2020-09-15</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 01:02:32 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.7</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Part 1&amp;#58; My home network journal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will be part of a series documenting the network component of my upcoming renovation of my new apartment. The apartment is over 20 years old hence a major overhaul is required and the renovation is a great opportunity to lay CAT6 to all the rooms in the house for the 1Gbps/10Gbps network 🤓.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My research began with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patnotebook.com/bto-networking-singapore/&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://patnotebook.com&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;patnotebook.com&lt;/a&gt; detailing the conversion of telephone points to RJ45 data points in newer BTO (Build to Order) flats in Singapore. Newer flats in Singapore have CAT6 cables already nicely laid in the house, however many of the points are terminated with a telephone jack instead of RJ45. Based on the article, it seems that BTO flats only have one point terminated as RJ45, which is definitely not enough 😁.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, I will have to lay my own cables and design my own network infrastructure since my flat is a legacy model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great networking and Ubiquiti resource is Evan McCann’s tech blog - &lt;a href=&quot;https://evanmccann.net/&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;McCann Tech&lt;/a&gt;. There are many nice articles that explain networking jargon in simple terms and breaks down the Ubiquiti universe in sizeable chunks. He is extremely detailed in doing breakdowns and making comparisons on the many Ubiquiti products. I would recommend his site as essential reading for whoever is considering putting together a Ubiquiti system!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recommended-mccann-reading-list&quot;&gt;Recommended McCann reading list&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://evanmccann.net/blog/unifi-ecosystem-overview&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;Ubiquiti’s UniFi Ecosystem Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://evanmccann.net/blog/2020/6/unifi-switches-explained&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;UniFi Switches Explained&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://evanmccann.net/blog/2020/6/unifi-switches-buyers-guide&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;UniFi Switch Comparison and Buyer’s Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://evanmccann.net/blog/unifi-ap-breakdown&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;UniFi Wireless Access Point Buyer’s Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://evanmccann.net/blog/home-network-tips&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;Wi-fi: Isn’t Magic Some Tips For Planning A Home Network&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://evanmccann.net/blog/2020/6/ubiquiti-faq&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;Ubiquiti FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to update with subsequent posts, but for now I’ve made a simple diagram detailing the essential hardware required for the network setup. I’ve decided to go full Ubiquiti for my first setup because it seems easy to put together for an ‘enterprise’ grade solution and is well regarded in the networking community. I won’t deny that it is overkill for a home environment but this project is too exciting to pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-hardware-diagram&quot;&gt;The hardware diagram&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/originals/Network_diagram.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Network diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2020-09-15</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-09/Home-Network</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-09/Home-Network</guid>
        
        <category>network</category>
        
        <category>ubiquiti</category>
        
        <category>unifi</category>
        
        <category>edgemax</category>
        
        <category>wifi</category>
        
        
        <category>network</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The website is &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; up and here is my first post!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to create a work site for awhile now and I’ve finally taken up the challenge after attending GA’s Intro to Coding: HTML &amp;amp; CSS Workshop. It was a short webinar that covered the fundamentals, which taught me enough to take the plunge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here it is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially considered Wordpress for its wide usage but ultimately chose a static site generator like &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll&lt;/strong&gt; for its quick deployment and little complexity. Static sites can be hosted directly on &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; through &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;GitHub pages&lt;/a&gt;. That means no hosting fees (!!!) and easy management of edits, thanks to versioning (which I’m still discovering).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;things-ive-learned-and-done-so-far&quot;&gt;Things I’ve learned and done so far&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to purchase a domain &lt;a href=&quot;https://namecheap.com/&quot; target=&quot;_ blank&quot;&gt;(namecheap)&lt;/a&gt; and point it to the host (&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Discovered &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; Desktop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better understand &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt; as a platform and its functions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set-up and create a simple &lt;strong&gt;Jekyll&lt;/strong&gt; site and host it on &lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to host the site locally for testing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to maintain the entire project on &lt;strong&gt;Atom&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some issues along the way, so I wouldn’t say it was an easy ride. Fortunately, nothing is too difficult for Google &amp;amp; Stack Overflow. I’ve learned plenty so far but there is still much to do and learn. I’ll update this page as I go along.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2020-09-15</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-07/First-Post</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/articles/2020-07/First-Post</guid>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>github</category>
        
        <category>website</category>
        
        <category>atom</category>
        
        <category>web hosting</category>
        
        <category>domain</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>website</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
